

I have always been fascinated by the idea of an electronic machine being faster than me to a degree of no comparison, and of course, the fact that Internet allows me to connect to a computer poles apart from me. Now after four years of learning, i understand most of the aspects of mentioned technologies with a strong grasp of theoretical aspects as well as using these information technologies in real life. I consider myself an efficient and systematic programmer and Engineer, who is familiar with different programming paradigms and is good at solving problems systematically to a degree where i find myself ready to go out there to face real challenges in the real world.



(+91) 9682690657



asrarpsi@gmail.com



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/asrarbhat/



https://github.com/asrarbhat/

Asrar Farooq Bhat

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science & Engineering



Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Skills

Programming

- Python + (Django)
- Java
- C
- C+-
- SQL (MYSQL)
- MongoDB
- JavaScript + (Node,React,Express)
- HTML/CSS/SCSS/JS

AI/MI /DI /DS

- Artificial Intelligence
- Data ScienceMachine Learning
- Deep Learning

Big Data/Cloud

- Hadoop Ecosystem
- Spark
- AWS
- Distributed Systems
- loT

Other

- Linux Administration
- Git/Github
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Bash Scripting
- Automation

Work Experience

Research Engineer Intern • Samsung Electronics

Feb 2022 - July 2022

I worked as a Research Engineer Intern for Samsung, where the job was to come up with innovative ideas and generate patents for the same. I presented multiple ideas, of which I documented two for the P team to generate patents.

Data Science Intern •Yoshops.com

Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

I worked as a Data Science intern for Yoshops and during my time there, i designed a webcrawler, and i automated resume filtering for HR, i automated banner production for products and worked on the autoreply system for the comments section.

Machine Learning Intern • Suvidha Foundation

Aug 2021- Sep 2021

I worked as a Machine Learning intern, where I was mainly working with Geographical data to figure out the humanitarian status of a given location. And I wrote two chapters for a book on machine learning for kids.

Data Analyst • Save Youth Save Future

Aug 2019- Sep 2021

I worked as a Data Analyst for an NGO. where I would design statistical experiments to get unbiased data, then summarize the collected data with statistics and visualizations, and infer the trends.

Education

2018 - 2022

Ramaiah Institute of Technology

Computer Science and Engineering 8.06/10

2013-2017

Government Higher Secondary Fatehgarh

10th: 85.2% 12th: 85.8%

Projects

Cryptographic System

I Came up with a new cryptographic algorithm provably exponential in time in terms of breaking it and implemented the same in python.

Web Crawler & Automated banners

I built a web crawler for a shopping website to get data for analysis and I automated banner production of products for marketing.

Automated Compilation

I invented a tool that compiles and runs your code automatically when changes occur to code and gives stats about the execution. It can be found on my Github under the automaton repository.

Powered by CakeResume